Guide to the Fred Friendly Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Writing, 1940-1996
  - Subseries II.3: Speeches, 1964-1996
    Friendly was frequently invited to college commencement ceremonies, professional conferences, and dedications. He also wrote eulogies honoring the lives of friends and colleagues. Most files in this subseries contain notes and drafts of speeches, as well as invitations and programs. They have been arranged alphabetically by title where possible, or by institution where no title exists.
    - Academy of Television Arts and Sciences Conference on TV and Ethics, 1987 March 6 (Box 91, Folder F.8)
    - Association of Schools of Journalism and Mass Communications, 1985 August 4 (Box 91, Folder F.9)
    - Alexander Hamilton Award Dinner, 1982 November 17 (Box 91, Folder F.10)
    - "ACLU: Judge It By Its Enemies"--ACLU of Hawaii, 1985 March 9 (Box 92, Folder F.1)
    - "The Administration, the Media and the Prime Time Rule," 1972 June 1 (Box 92, Folder F.2)
    - American Film Institute, 1983 November 4 (Box 92, Folder F.3)
    - American Jewish Congress National Biennial Convention, 1970 May 22 (Box 92, Folder F.4)
    - American Jewish Congress, 1978 June 21 (Box 92, Folder F.5)
    - American Society of Magazine Editors, 1973 May 24 (Box 92, Folder F.6)
    - American Women in Radio and Television, Inc., 1964 April 30 (Box 92, Folder F.7)
    - Anti-Defamation League First Amendment Freedoms Award Dinner, 1975 September 17 (Box 92, Folder F.8)
    - Anti-Defamation League Tribute Dinner Honoring Arch L. Madsen, 1993 September 8 (Box 92, Folder F.9)
    - APA on Television Programming, 1988 (Box 92, Folder F.10)
    - "Appointment in Samarra...In Nebraska," 1979 April 16 (Box 92, Folder F.11)
    - "Appointment at Samarra...University," 1969 June 8 (Box 92, Folder F.12)
    - "Argument in Indianapolis," 1970 January 24 (Box 92, Folder F.13)
    - "Argument in Indianapolis: Ratifying the First Amendment 182 Years Late," 1973 (Box 92, Folder F.14)
    - "Argument in Indianapolis, or the Longest Scheduled Meeting in American History," 1973 October 13, (4 Folders) (Box 92, Folder F.15-18)
    - Armstrong Awards, 1973 March 24 (Box 93, Folder F.1)
    - Army War College, 1987 September 21 (Box 93, Folder F.2)
    - Art Director's Club Hall of Fame Induction of Ben Shahn, 1988 October 21 (Box 93, Folder F.3)
    - "The Attempted Politicization of Broadcast Journalism," 1973 February 2 (Box 93, Folder F.5)
    - Lerrone Bennett Speech, 1970 (Box 93, Folder F.6)
    - "The Bill of Rights: The Greatest Afterthought in History," 1982 July 9 (Box 93, Folder F.7)
    - "Brandeis, the First Amendment and the Voices We Hate," 1990 February 2 (Box 93, Folder F.8)
    - "Breakfast of Business Champions," WNET/Thirteen (public radio), 1989 November 14 (Box 93, Folder F.9)
    - "Bridge Builders and Gatekeepers," 13 September 1982 (Box 93, Folder F.10)
    - Brigham Young University, 1991 April 3-5 (Box 93, Folder F.11)
    - Broadcast Journalism, 1966 (Box 93, Folder F.12)
    - Calvin College, 1973 September 27 (Box 93, Folder F.13)
    - "Can Chicago Survive Its Miracles," WTTW (public television), 1970 January 15 (Box 93, Folder F.14)
    - "Can We Manage Our Miracles?" 1970 April 11 (Box 93, Folder F.15)
    - Carnegie Mellon Commencement Speech, 1986 May 12 (Box 93, Folder F.16)
    - "Celebrating David Stein," 1993 January 22 (Box 94, Folder F.1)
    - The Celeste Bartos Forum, 1989 October 16 (Box 94, Folder F.2)
    - Cheshire Academy Commencement Exercises, 1989 June 3 (Box 94, Folder F.3)
    - Chicago Historical Society, 1987 September 12 (Box 94, Folder F.4)
    - Colorado Bar Association Luncheon, 1984 September 28 (Box 94, Folder F.5)
    - Columbia College Commencement, 1986 May 30 (Box 94, Folder F.6)
    - Columbia University Journalism School Commencement, 1988 September 6 (Box 94, Folder F.7)
    - Columbia University Law School Commencement, 1984 May 15 (Box 94, Folder F.8)
    - Commemoration of the 200th Anniversary of the Publication of the Federalist Papers, 1987 October 27 (Box 94, Folder F.9)
    - "Conflicts Between the Law and the Media," 1974 June 7 (Box 94, Folder F.10)
    - "The Constitution," undated (Box 94, Folder F.11)
    - "The Constitution: Terrorism and the News Media," 1985 October 15 (Box 94, Folder F.12)
    - "Could the Boston Tea Party Be Televised?" 1970 February 25 (Box 94, Folder F.13)
    - "Could There Ever Be Another Murrow?" 1986 January 14 (Box 94, Folder F.14)
    - "Counselor-At-Law or Gun For Hire?" 1973 (Box 95, Folder F.1)
    - "The Courtroom v. the Newsroom," 1975 May 13 (Box 95, Folder F.2)
    - "Dedication of the Rogers Communication Center," Public Communication Foundation for North Texas, 1975 September 18 (Box 95, Folder F.3)
    - Delia Smith Mares Lecture, Bryn Mawr College, 1981 October 21 (Box 95, Folder F.4)
    - "Don't Just Swear to Uphold the Constitution-Understand It," 1986-1987, (3 Folders) (Box 95, Folder F.5-7)
    - Duquesne University Commencement Speech, 1985 May 10 (Box 95, Folder F.8)
    - Edward R. Murrow High School--Lecture, 1987 (Box 95, Folder F.9)
    - "Edward R. Murrow's Legacy and Today's Media," 1971 April 16 (Box 95, Folder F.10)
    - Irving Fain's Bar Mitzvah, 1993 April 17 (Box 95, Folder F.11)
    - "Fifty Years Later: The Minnesota Case that Shaped the Constitution," 1981 June 5 (Box 95, Folder F.12)
    - The Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy at Tufts, 1974 (Box 95, Folder F.13)
    - Florida State University Commencement, 1986 December (Box 95, Folder F.14)
    - Floyd Abrams Tribute Dinner, The Lawyers Division, State of Israel Bonds, 1986 February 25 (Box 95, Folder F.15)
    - Fred Friendly First Amendment Award Luncheon, Quinnipiac College, 1996 May 8 (Box 95, Folder F.16)
    - "Funds, Pluralism and the Real Light on the End of the Tube," undated (Box 95, Folder F.17)
    - "Future and Performance of Press," 1983 January 26 (Box 95, Folder F.18)
    - George Chaplin Scholar in Residence Lecture, 1989 December 12 (Box 95, Folder F.19)
    - "The Golden Age of Dissent and the Oregon Connection," 1978 June 11 (Box 95, Folder F.20)
    - Guildhall Lecture, 1967 October 24 (Box 96, Folder F.1)
    - Guilford County Dinner, 1971 January 5 (Box 96, Folder F.2)
    - Hadassah Convention, 1973 August 27 (Box 96, Folder F.3)
    - Hamilton School at Wheeler, 1995 April 7 (Box 96, Folder F.4)
    - "Hard Choices for a Free People," 1984 May 23 (Box 96, Folder F.5)
    - "Headlines, Deadlines and Bottom Lines," 1985 April 22 (Box 96, Folder F.6)
    - "The Hour News: A Leap of Faith v. The Bottom Line," 1982 March 27 (Box 96, Folder F.7)
    - "How to Lose Your Job," 1983 February 5 (Box 96, Folder F.8)
    - "Hubert H. Humphrey First Amendment Freedoms Prize," June 1988 June 10 (Box 96, Folder F.9)
    - "If I Had My Career in Broadcast Journalism to Start Over Again in August 1986," 1986 August 29 (Box 96, Folder F.10)
    - "If It Weren't for the Judges," 1982-1983 (Box 97, Folder F.1-6)
    - "Impeachment and Trial? Test for the President and Television," 1974 June 15 (Box 97, Folder F.7)
    - Interchurch Center Trustees Dinner, 1987, 1992 (Box 97, Folder F.8)
    - "Job Announcement," 1964 (Box 97, Folder F.9)
    - "Journalism at a Time of Perpetual Crisis, or, Little Red Riding Hood From the Wolf's Point of View," 1980 March 22, (2 Folders) (Box 97, Folder F.10-11)
    - "Judges Before the Court of Public Opinion," 1978 June 8 (Box 98, Folder F.1)
    - "Judges, Journalists and the Constitution," 1984-1985, (3 Folders) (Box 98, Folder F.2-4)
    - "Judges and Journalists: Whose End of the Boat Is Sinking?" 1982, (2 Folders) (Box 98, Folder F.5-6)
    - Eulogy for Sophia J. Kleegman, undated (includes audio cassettes) (Box 98, Folder F.7)
    - Tribute to David Kuhn, 1994 April 29 (Box 98, Folder F.8)
    - Lewis and Clark Commencement, 1990 June 10 (Box 98, Folder F.9)
    - Mowry Lowe Eulogy, 1973 October 3 (Box 98, Folder F.10)
    - "Malice in Wonderland," 1983 November 12 (Box 98, Folder F.11)
    - Marist College Commencement, 1990 May 19 (Box 98, Folder F.12)
    - "The Meaning of Freedom," 1991 September 26 (Box 98, Folder F.13)
    - "Memorial Day Massacre," 1971 (Box 98, Folder F.14)
    - University of Michigan, 1971 March 10 (Box 99, Folder F.1)
    - "The Murrow Legacy, Twenty-Five Years After," 1990 January 25 (Box 99, Folder F.2)
    - National Education Association Public-Cable Seminar, 1972 May 5 (Box 99, Folder F.3)
    - National Press Club, 1972 June 1 (Box 99, Folder F.4)
    - "Near v. Minnesota-A Half Century Later," 1978 October 21 (Box 99, Folder F.5)
    - "The Nervous Breakdown of the First Amendment," 1973-1974, (5 Folders) (Box 99, Folder F.6-10)
    - New York Law School Remarks, 1987 September 14 (Box 100, Folder F.1)
    - Nichols College Commencement Speeches, 1967, 1989 (Box 100, Folder F.2)
    - Nieman Foundation for Journalism, 1981 (Box 100, Folder F.3)
    - The Nightly News: A Leap of Faith v. the Bottom Line, 1982 March 10, (3 Folders) (Box 100, Folder F.4-6)
    - "No Foundation All the Way Down the Line...," 1988 December 29 (Box 100, Folder f.7)
    - Opening by Charles Ogletree at Public School 165, 1990 November 30 (Box 100, Folder f.8)
    - "On Ceil Steins' Receiving the B'nai Brith Humanitarian Award," 1993 November 28 (Box 100, Folder f.9)
    - "On Judging the Judges," 1978 March 20 (Box 100, Folder f.10)
    - "On Prime Time," undated (Box 100, Folder f.11)
    - "Order in the Courtroom and Freedom in the Newsroom," 1980 July 8 (Box 100, Folder f.12)
    - "Our Crisis in Ethics," Emerson College Commencement Speech, 1987 May 11 (Box 100, Folder f.13)
    - "Overheating the First Amendment," 1983 March 12 (Box 101, Folder F.1)
    - John Meredith Patterson Eulogy, 1975 December 17 (Box 101, Folder F.2)
    - "Patterson/Bliss," undated (Box 101, Folder F.3)
    - PBS Advertising and Promotion Conference, 1988 June 6 (Box 101, Folder F.4)
    - PBS Annual Meeting, 1981 June 29 (Box 101, Folder F.5)
    - "Point of View," 1988 June 23 (Box 101, Folder F.6)
    - "Power of the Press: Blessing or Threat," 1983 February 17 (Box 101, Folder F.7)
    - Practicing Law Institute, undated (Box 101, Folder F.8)
    - Princeton University, 1977 October 7 (Box 101, Folder F.9)
    - Princeton University Conference, 1970 January (Box 101, Folder F.10)
    - Public Relations Society of America Remarks, 1970 November 16 (Box 101, Folder F.11)
    - Public Television Annual Meeting, 1985 May 17 (Box 101, Folder F.12)
    - "The Present Minded Professor," 1968 November 29 (Box 101, Folder F.13)
    - "Rabbi William Braude: A Very Personal Reflection," 1988 February 28 (Box 101, Folder F.14)
    - "Reporter's Privilege Law: Shield of Damocles?" 1973 August 6 (Box 101, Folder F.15)
    - Reporting Public Affairs in the Year 2004 Symposium, 1984 October 5 (Box 101, Folder F.16)
    - Rhode Island Campaign to Remember, 1987 October 5 (Box 101, Folder F.17)
    - Riverdale Press Office Reopening, 1989 September 27 (Box 101, Folder F.18)
    - Riverdale School Commencement, 1972 June 9 (Box 101, Folder F.19)
    - "Self-Inflicted Wounds: Judges and Journalists," 1983 November 9, (3 Folders) (Box 102, Folder F.1-3)
    - "Should Government Play a Role in Assisting Or Subsidizing News Media?" 1982 March 18 (Box 102, Folder F.4)
    - Silurian Society Talk, 1994 November 16 (Box 102, Folder F.5)
    - Silver Anniversary Banquet, 1973 February 2 (Box 102, Folder F.6)
    - The Smithsonian Resident Associate Program Lecture Series, 1988 October 11 (Box 102, Folder F.7)
    - "Some Second Sober Thoughts on Vice President Agnew," 1969 November 21 (Box 102, Folder F.8)
    - Southern Utah State College Commencement, 1986 June 7 (Box 102, Folder F.9)
    - "The Spirit of '76 and the Next President of the United States," 1972 December 6 (Box 102, Folder F.10)
    - Samuel Standard Eulogy, 1970 October 28, (3 Folders) (Box 102, Folder F.11-13)
    - Elaine Strauss Eulogy, 1982 July (Box 103, Folder F.1)
    - "Television and Terrorism: What Went Right, What Went Wrong," 1985 October 9 (Box 103, Folder F.2)
    - Thomas Edison State College Commencement, 1991 October (Box 103, Folder F.3)
    - Lonnie Layton Thomas Memorial, 1971 (Box 103, Folder F.4)
    - Thomas Paine National Historical Association, 1994 April 12 (Box 103, Folder F.5)
    - University of Utah Commencement, 1985 June 8 (Box 103, Folder F.6)
    - Utah State Bar Speech, 1987 August 4 (Box 103, Folder F.7)
    - United States Holocaust Memorial Museum Dedication, 1993 April 22 (Box 103, Folder F.8)
    - U.S. Communications Subcommittee of the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science and Transportation, 1988 April 27 (Box 103, Folder F.9)
    - U.S. House Interstate and Foreign Commerce Committee, 1970 April 27 (Box 103, Folder F.10)
    - U.S. House Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East of the Committee on Foreign Affairs, 1985 July 30 (Box 103, Folder F.11)
    - U.S. Joint Subcommittee on Congressional Operations, 1974 April 9 (Box 103, Folder F.12)
    - U.S. Senate Committee on Commerce, Science and Transportation, 1982 November 19 (Box 103, Folder F.13)
    - U.S. Subcommittee on Constitutional Rights-Senate Committee on the Judiciary, 1971 October 12 (Box 103, Folder F.14)
    - U.S. Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance of the Committee on Energy and Commerce, 1987 April 28, (2 Folders) (Box 103, Folder F.15-16)
    - U.S. Third Circuit Judicial Conference Luncheon, 1984 September 18 (Box 103, Folder F.17)
    - "Watergate and the Media," 1973 (Box 104, Folder F.1)
    - "When War Comes, Whither the First Amendment?"1991 January 22 (Box 104, Folder F.2)
    - William O. Douglas Lecture, 1985 November 7 (Box 104, Folder F.3)
    - University of Wisconsin Commencement, 1971 June 14 (Box 104, Folder F.4)
    - Wooster College, 1982 June 13 (Box 104, Folder F.5)
    - "World Without Distance," 1966 October 24 (Box 104, Folder F.6)
    - Yale University's Daily News Dinner, 1984 November 9 (Box 104, Folder F.7)
- Series III: Media and Society Seminars, 1974-1996
  One of Friendly's many achievements was the creation of Media and Society Seminars (MSS). Conducted by Columbia University, the seminar series brought politicians, doctors, journalists, and other specialists together for moderated round-table discussions on challenging ethical dilemmas. Friendly stressed that the goal was, "not to make up anybody's mind, but to open minds; to make the agony of decision-making so intense that you can only escape it by thinking." From the time of its founding in 1974 until Friendly stepped down as producer in 1992, MSS orchestrated over 600 seminars on diverse topics including medical malpractice, affirmative action, abortion, and business ethics. Many of these were televised on PBS, and several were also offered on VHS tapes, along with workbooks and discussion questions to be used as "telecourse" series in high school and college classrooms. The program was later renamed Fred Friendly Seminars in his honor.
  The series is comprised primarily of seminar transcripts, but also includes proposals and planning notes, research notes, film production information, promotional packets for telecourses, and drafts of "hypotheticals"—the scenarios that provided the focus of each discussion. Items have been arranged by seminar title.
  - AIDS in Society, 1988 (Box 105)
    - Brochures and Outlines (Box 105, Folder F.1)
    - Transcript (Box 105, Folder F.2)
  - The Agony of Decision --Notes, 1991 (Box 105, Folder F.3)
  - American Business Association Meeting--Notes, 1991 (Box 105, Folder F.4)
  - Anatomy of a Libel Case: Business vs. the Media, 1984-1985
    - Research Notes, 1985 (Box 105, Folder F.5)
    - Promotional Items, 1984 (Box 105, Folder F.6)
    - Transcripts, 1984, (2 Folders) (Box 105, Folder F.7-8)
    - Transcripts, 1984 February 4 (Box 106, Folder F.1-2)
  - Balancing Health Care Costs --Notes and Seminar Packet, 1986 (Box 106, Folder F.3)
  - Bridging the Gap --Proposal, 1989 (Box 106, Folder F.4)
  - Book Publishing and the First Amendment --Conference Report, 1975 April 18-20 (Box 106, Folder F.5)
  - Broadcast Media and the Law, 1980 July 29-30
    - Brochures and Programs (Box 106, Folder F.6)
    - Transcripts, (3 Folders) (Folder F.7-9)
    - Broadcasting and the Constitution --Research Notes and Program, 1987 (Box Box 107, Folder F.1)
    - Business and the Entrepreneurial American City, 1988
    - Research and Panel Topics, (5 Folders) (Box 107, Folder F.2-6)
    - Symposium Outline (Box 107, Folder F.7)
  - Business Ethics Seminar--Transcript, undated (Box 108, Folder F.1)
  - Changing Times/Hard Choices, 1991, (2 Folders) (Folder F.2-3)
    - Discussion Guide, undated (Box 108, Folder F.4)
    - Transcript, 1982, (2 Folders) (Box 108, Folder F.5-6)
  - The Constitution, 1987 (Box 108, Folder F.7)
  - Constitution Seminar Proposal, 1979 (Folder F.8)
    - Promotional Items, 1984 (Box 108)
  - The Constitution: That Delicate Balance (Box 109)
    - Promotional Items, 1984 (Box 109, Folder F.1)
    - Photographs, 1984 (Box 109, Folder F.2)
    - Correspondence, 1984, (2 Folders) (Box 109, Folder F.3-4)
    - Reviews, 1983-1984 (Box 109, Folder f.5)
    - Video Editing Information, 1984 (Box 109, Folder f.6)
    - Workshops, 1984, (3 Folders) (Box 109, Folder f.7-9)
  - The Constitution: That Delicate Balance (Box 110)
    - Workshops, 1984, (8 Folders) (Box 110, Folder F.1-8)
  - The Constitution: That Delicate Balance (Box 111)
    - Education Telecourse Curriculum Use Report, 1984 (Box 111, Folder F.1)
    - Discussion Guides, 1984 (Box 111, Folder F.2)
    - Correspondence Regarding Book, 1984 (Box 111, Folder F.3)
    - Transcripts
      - Program 1: "The President vs. Congress: Executive Privilege and the Delegation of Powers," 1983 (Box 111, Folder F.4)
      - Program 2: "War Powers: The President and Congress," 1984 (Box 111, Folder F.5)
      - Program 3: "Nomination, Election and Succession of the President," 1984 (Box 111, Folder F.6)
      - Program 4: "Criminal Justice and a Defendant's Right to a Fair Trial," 1983 January 12 (Box 111, Folder F.7)
      - Program 6: "Crime and Punishment," 1984 February (Box 111, Folder F.8)
      - Program 6: "Crime and Punishment," 1984 February 8 (Box 112, Folder F.1)
      - Program 8 "National Security and Freedom of the Press," 1984 (Box 112, Folder F.2)
      - Program 9: "School Prayer, Gun Control, and the Right to Assemble," 1983 January 19 (Box 112, Folder F.3)
      - Program 10: "The Sovereign Self: Right to Live, Right to Die," 1984 (Box 112, Folder F.4)
      - Program 12: "Affirmative Action and Reverse Discrimination," 1983 February 2 (Box 112, Folder F.5)
      - Program 13: "Federalism: The National Government vs. The States," 1984 (Box 112, Folder F.6)
      - "The Trail from Independence Hall: The Constitution in the Classroom," undated (Box 112, Folder F.7)
      - Case Studies 1A and 1B, undated (Box 112, Folder F.8)
      - Case Study 1B, undated (Box 113, Folder F.1)
      - "State Terror," 1984 January 9 (Box 113, Folder F.2)
      - "Separation of Church and State," 1984 (Box 113, Folder F.3)
  - Containment and the Future --Program, 1985 November 7-8 (Box 113, Folder F.4)
  - Criminal Justice, the News Media, and the Constitution --Program and Notes, 1987 (Box 113, Folder F.5)
  - The Crisis in American Healthcare --Proposal, 1991 (Box 113, Folder F.6)
  - A Decade of Hard Choices --TV scripts, 1992 (Folder F.7)
    - Seminar 1--Transcript, 1989 November 18 (Box 113)
    - Seminars 2-3--Transcripts, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 114, Folder F.1-2)
  - Ethical Decision Making in America --Proposal, 1986 (Folder F.3)
    - Proposal, 1985 April 1 (Box 114)
    - Research Notes and Articles, 1985, (3 Folders) (Box 114, Folder F.5-7)
  - Ethics in America (Box 115)
    - Production Agreement, 1984 (Box 115, Folder F.1)
    - Production Binder, 1987, (2 Folders) (Box 115, Folder F.2-3)
    - Telecourse Promotional Items, 1988-1989 (Box 115, Folder F.4)
    - Seminar Participant Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 115, Folder F.5)
  - Ethics in America (Box 116)
    - Workshops--General, 1988-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 116, Folder F.1-2)
    - Promotional Brochures and Packet, 1989 (Box 116, Folder F.3)
    - Transcripts
      - "Ethics in Government," circa 1989, (2 Folders) (Box 116, Folder F.4-5)
      - "Hours 1-2," undated (Box 116, Folder F.6)
      - "Hour 3," undated (Box 117, Folder F.1)
      - "To Defend a Killer," circa 1989 (Box 117, Folder F.2)
      - Business Ethics, 1989 (Box 117, Folder F.3)
      - "The Human Family: Ethics in Personal Relationships," 1987 (Box 117, Folder F.4)
      - "Autonomy vs. Paternalism: The Pregnant Cancer Patient and the Unborn Child," circa 1989 (Box 117, Folder F.5)
      - "Truth and Justice: The Adversary System in Civil Litigation," undated (Box 117, Folder F.6)
      - "The Victim and the Accused," circa 1989 (Box 118, Folder F.1)
      - "Tradeoffs in the Laboratory: The Ethics of Medical Research," circa 1989 (Box 118, Folder F.2)
      - "Hour 1," circa 1989 (Box 118, Folder F.3)
      - "Hour 3," circa 1989 (Box 118, Folder 4)
      - Case Studies 1-2, circa 1989, (2 Folders) (Box 118, Folder F.5-6)
      - "An Introduction to Ethical Reasoning"--Audio Programs, circa 1989 (Box 118, Folder F.7)
  - Ethics Forum, 1991 (Box 119, Folder F.1)
    - Case Study 1, 1983 April 11 (Box 119)
    - "Terrorism," 1982 November 6, (2 Folders) (Box 119, Folder F.3-4)
    - "Privacy," undated (Box 119, Folder F.5)
    - Panel #3, 1982 November 17 (Box 119, Folder F.6)
    - Eyeball to Eyeball--Transcript, 1990 (Box 119, Folder F.7)
  - The Federalist Papers --Proposal, 1996 (Box 120, Folder F.1)
  - Hard Choices for Law Enforcement --Planning Materials, 1995 (Box 120, Folder F.2)
  - Hard Drugs, Hard Choices
    - Research Notes and Articles, 1990, (3 Folders) (Box 120, Folder F.3-5)
    - Planning Material, 1990 (Box 120, Folder F.6)
    - Promotional Packet and Reviews, 1990 (Box 120, Folder F.7)
  - Home: A Place in the World--Correspondence, 1990 (Box 121, Folder F.1)
    - "The Emergency, Censorship and the Press in India: A Retrospective"--Transcript of Speech, 1978 November 4 (Box 121, Folder F.2)
    - Case Studies I-III, 1978, (4 Folders) (Box 121, Folder F.3-5)
    - Untitled Case Studies, 1978 (Box 121, Folder F.6)
  - If Women are Doing so Well, Where are They on Your Masthead?-- Research Notes, 1988 (Folder F.7)
    - Planning Materials, 1986 (Box 121)
  - In the Face of Terrorism (Box 122)
    - Conference Outline, 1986 (Box 122, Folder F.1)
    - Conference Packet, 1986 (Box 122, Folder F.2)
    - Panel I, Part I: "Ranean: Rescue and Response,"--Transcript, 1986 September 27, (2 Folders) (Box 122, Folder F.3-4)
    - Panel III: "Violence in Northern Shamrock: Terrorism or Civil War?" 1986 September 27 (Box 122, Folder F.5)
    - Panel IV: "Terrorism at Home: Challenges for a Free and Open Society," 1986 September 27 (Box 122, Folder F.6)
  - Issues of Professionalism: The Limits on Zealous Advocacy and Beyond --Planning Materials and Program, 1986 (Box 123, Folder F.1)
  - Judges, Ethics, and Hard Choices--Notes and Hypotheticals, 1993 (Box 123, Folder F.2)
  - Annual Judicial Conference--Program and Hypotheticals, 1980 (Box 123, Folder F.3)
  - Law, Crime, Education, and the Press --Planning Materials and Notes, 1988 (Box 123, Folder F.4)
  - Law, Order, and the Constitution --Transcript, 1987 (Box 123, Folder F.5)
  - Law and Society --Transcript, 1987 (Box 123, Folder F.6)
  - Libel Seminar --Transcript, undated (Box 123, Folder F.7)
  - Making of War --Transcript, undated (Folder F.8)
    - Planning Notes, 1986 (Box 123)
    - Research Notes and Hypotheticals, 1986, (2 Folders) (Box 123, Folder F.10-11)
  - Managing Our Miracles (Box 124)